Kristel Tatiana Segura Gamez

San Jose, Costa Rica



krisama21@gmail.com



85371754



linkedin.com/in/segakris

Summary

With 7+ years of experience in the market, I have develop Leadership, Management for new Software Solutions during the entire SDLC, Teamwork, Systems Integration Solutions Development., find spaces for Upgrades in already in use Software, keep software solution safe out of vulnerabilities, by applying the best development practices, worked with Several Code languages, Database Engines, and cloud Technologies.

Active Volunteer at Cenfotec University as a coach and teacher for new students to help them to improve their hard and soft skills.

Experience



Senior Software Development Engineer

Equifax

Jul 2021 - Present (2 years 2 months)

- Increased by 400% productivity of the team by upgrading internal company task that were manual to fully Automated Solutions.
- Lead Development projects and design upgrades to existing Programs
- Design, Develop and Implement Event Driven Designed Solutions to automate ingestions for data pipelines.
- Handle diferent application releases using the CI/CD strategy for diferent environments (PRODUCTION, UAT, NPE) using Jenkins, Terraform, Nexus, GCP Nexus.
- Define and own accountability in estimation process, use case specifications, reviews of test plans and test cases, requirements, and project planning.
- Design, develop, test, deploy, maintain, and improve software per given business requirements using the following technologies: (JAVA EE, XML, JSON, API'S, YAML, MAVEN, SECURITY, HADOOP, SPARK(Avro))
- Development oriented to cloud technologies specifically using Google Cloud Platform stack like: Buckets, GKE, Dataproc, Cloud Functions, Cloud Run PUB/SUB, Data Proc, Big Query, GKE, Fire Store (Datastore mode).

Senior Software Developer Analyst --- Senior Software Developer Team Lead Accenture

Mar 2020 - Jul 2021 (1 year 5 months)

- Successfully Migrated Old CRM Systems to AEM 6.5 and exceeded the customer criteria.
- Design customize API's using the following tech Stack (AEM, Java, Java EE, Maven, Spring Boot, XML, HTML, Json, JCR, Apache Libs (Jackson, Jackrabbit, Commons, OSGi), Rest, SOA).
- Design, customize build, debug, and deploy Software Applications based on open-source libraries such as Apache Kafka, Apache Camel, Zookeeper.
- Work directly with business users and product owners to design and implement solutions based on product requirements.

• Lead the technical planning & requirements gathering phases including estimate, develop, test, manage projects, and deliver using tools such as Jira, Git (GitHub).

Teaching Assistant Professor

Universidad Cenfotec

Jan 2018 - Jan 2020 (2 years 1 month)

- Assist /Teach courses (labs) at the undergraduate level.
- Create workshop classes for the following Subjects: Programming 1 and 2, Data structures and Algorithms.

Software Developer Engineer --- Software Engineer Team Lead

Peter Paul Inc.

Apr 2015 - Jul 2019 (4 years 4 months)

- 100+ Customer's Customized Software developed (each customer customized the modules based on their needs)
- Participate in software product review and team meetings.
- Design, develop, implement, and debug software using Java EE, Maven, Spring Boot, NodeJS (Mongoose, Morgan, Express, Discriminator, Passport, Bycript Node mailer).
- Troubleshoots production problems related to software applications.
- Addresses problems of systems integration, compatibility, and multiple platforms.
- Interact with members of other teams during design, development, and maintenance of deliverables.

Education

Universidad Cenfotec

Barchelor's Engineering Degree., Software Development Jan 2017 - May 2023

Universidad Cenfotec

Software Developer Technical Degree, Information Technology 2019 - 2021

Greencore Solutions

Associate SysAdmin in Linux Environments., SysAdmin Linux 2018 - 2019

Licenses & Certifications

Adobe Certified Expert - Adobe Experience Manager Sites Developer - Adobe Issued Aug 2020 - Expires Aug 2022

Skills

Spanish • Agile Methodologies • Core Java • Software Development • Product Development • Crossfunctional Team Leadership • Software Project Management • Maven • Spring MVC • Java